(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
- The Cybermen.  - Shh.
- 是赛博人  - 嘘
- (WHISPERING) Where do they come from?
- I don't know, Jamie,
- 他们从哪里来的？  - 我不知道, Jamie
but they're here, aren't they?
但他们现在在这里了, 对吧
Come on, let's go back to the canoe.
快来, 我们到fixme 后面去
What did you find out?
你发现了什么？
- Some old friends of ours are here, Zoe.
- Who?
- 我们的一些老朋友在这里  - 谁？
- The Cybermen.
- Yes, I'm afraid it's true, Zoe.
- 赛博人  - 是的, 恐怕这是真的, Zoe
- That's what you suspected, wasn't it?
- What on Earth are Cybermen?
- 你在怀疑的就是这个, 对吧？  - 赛博人到底是什么？
They're from another world. Inhuman killers.
他们来自另外一个世界, 没有人性的杀手
You...You're serious?
你...说的是真的？
We've met Cybermen before and seen what they can do.
我们以前遭遇过赛博人, 见过他们的所作所为
Where exactly are they and how many?
他们具体是在哪儿？有多少？
- JAMIE: At Vaughn's headquarters in London...
- Hundreds of them, probably thousands.
- 在 Vaughn 的伦敦总部  - 有数百个, 可能上千
ZOE: So Vaughn's helping them.
看来 Vaughn 在帮他们
So that's what those UFOs were.
But there've been hundreds of those sightings.
看来那些 UFO 出自那个地方, 但目击报告有几百起
Aye, they must have quite an army by now.
是, 他们目前肯定有很大一支队伍了
- The thing is, where are they hiding them all?
- I don't know, Jamie.
- 问题是, 他们被藏在哪里？  - 我不知道, Jamie
- Captain, where's the Brigadier?
- At the Ministry of Defence.
- 队长, 准将在哪里？  - 在国防部
I'll get on to him immediately
and tell him what you discovered.
我立刻跟他联系, 告诉他你们发现的情况
No, no, Captain.
不, 不, 队长
The people who went into Vaughn's Headquarters
那些进入过 Vaughn 总部的人
- were different when they came out, weren't they?
- Yes.
- 他们出来时有些不一样了, 对吧？  - 是的
- Do you think they're been controlled, Doctor?
- Controlled?
- 你觉得他们被控制了, 博士？  - 被控制了？
Yes, the Cybermen have means of controlling people's minds.
是的, 赛博人有控制人思想的手段
They appear to be almost normal,
but they're not, they're controlled.
他们看起来基本正常, 但其实不是, 他们被控制了
- Who is the Brigadier immediately answerable to?
- Major-General Rutlidge.
- 准将直接对谁汇报？  - 少将 Rutlidge
No cause for alarm?
Billy, do you realise what's happened?
没有找到警报缘由吗？Billy, 你明白是发生了什么事吗？
They tried to shoot down one of my helicopters.
他们试图击落我们的一架直升机
You were trespassing over their top-security area.
你们试图闯入他们的最高机密区域
Oh, for heaven's sake.
噢, 老天爷啊
If you can't trust a UNIT force, who can you trust?
如果你连 UNIT 都信不过, 你能信谁？
There's nothing we...
没有什么我们...
- What's the matter?
- Oh. Nothing. Nothing at all.
- 怎么了？  - 噢, 没事, 完全没事
Look, Billy, Vaughn's a powerful chap, I know that.
你看, Billy, Vaughn 是个有能量的家伙, 我知道的
But surely we can at least
request a thorough investigation.
但我们至少应该可以申请进行全面调查啊
This isn't our province.
这不在我们职权范围内
- Well, then whose province is it?
- It's no good getting angry about this.
- 那, 在谁职权范围内？  - 为这事生气并不值得
You must see this from my point of view.
你必须在我的角度来考虑这个问题
All you've given me are vague reports,
你所能给我的都是模糊的报告
- nothing conclusive, no proof.
- No proof!
- 没有确定的, 没有证据  - 没有证据！
I'm sure this is all a misunderstanding.
I'll talk to the C in C of internal security myself.
我肯定这都是误会．我会亲自同总司令沟通内部安全的问题
But, Billy, talk isn't going to help.
但是, Bily, 沟通并没有什么帮助
I want some sort of action, and I want it now.
我想要的是某种行动, 并且现在就要
At least get the civil authorities to investigate.
至少要拿到启动调查的授权
You'll have to leave this matter with me.
你就只能把这个问题交给我了fixme
Will I?
是么？
If you're thinking of going to the C in C yourself,
如果你想自己去找总司令
I shouldn't bother, you'll be wasting your time.
我不会干涉, 你只是在浪费自己的时间
So you're going to do nothing?
这么说你什么也打算做？
- What sort of hold has Vaughn got on you?
- Vaughn? I...
- Vaughn 拿到了你什么把柄？  - Vaughn? 我...
Brigadier, your UNIT force will take no precipitous
action without top-priority permission.
准将, 你的 UNIT 小组没有拿到最高授权之前不得擅自行动
- That is an order.  - I see, sir.
- 这是命令  - 我明白了, 长官
Well, you can override my authority
but not that of UNIT Central Command.
不过, 你可以压制我的权力, 但压制不了 UNIT 指挥中心
I'm sending a full report to them in Geneva.
我要向日内瓦递交一份完整的报告
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Have Gregory work with Professor Watkins on the machine.
让 Gregory 配合 Watkins 教授去做那台机器
Yes, Mr Vaughn.
好的, Vaughn 先生
No, wait.
不, 等等
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
- VAUGHN: What is it, Rutlidge?
- The UNIT group.
- 什么事, Rutlidge?  - 是 UNIT 的小组
- Well?
- There'll be trouble. I can't stop it.
- 怎么了？  - 会有麻烦了, 我阻止不了
- Why not? You have authority to.
- I have no authority outside this country.
- 为什么不行？你有这个权力  - 出了这个国家我就没权管了
A report is being made to UNIT Central Control.
他们已经向 UNIT 指挥中心递交了报告
They're bound to investigate and take action.
他们肯定要展开调查, 展开行动了
DOCTOR: You see, a network of tunnels underneath London.
你看, 一张伦敦地下的隧道网络
BRIGADIER: And that's where you think they might be?
你觉得他们可能在那里面？
Yes.
是的？
And look. There's a main flood-relief sewer
running right underneath the warehouse.
看, 这里有一个主要的泄洪渠, 正好在仓库的下面
Yes, but if there's water in the sewers,
wouldn't that affect them?
是的, 但如果下水道里面有水的, 他们不会受到影响吗？
Oh, no, no. Besides, many of these tunnels are dry
噢, 不, 不会．而且, 很多隧道都是干的/?
and only flood during heavy rainfall.
只有在暴雨的时候才会积水
What do we do? Pray for a cloudburst?
那我们怎么弄？等着倾盆大雨的到来？
Miss Watkins, this could be very serious.
Watkins 小姐, 这是非常严肃的事情
I'm sorry, but, well,
it's a pretty fantastic story to swallow.
对不起, 不过, 这事太离奇了, 难以让人接受
Yes, but so was the attack from the Yeti,
but nevertheless it happened.
是的, 雪怪袭击的事情也是这样, 不管怎么都真实发生了
With all due respect, sir, she's right.
No one believed in the Yetis until they saw them.
不揣冒昧, 长官, 她说得对．在看见雪怪之前是没有人相信的
If you go to Central Command with this story,
they'll think you're mad.
如果你到指挥中心去讲这个故事, 他们会认为你疯了
Yes. Yes, Jimmy, you're right.
是的, 是的, Jimmy, 你说得对
'Course, what we really need is
some sort of evidence, some proof.
当然, 我们真正需要的是某种迹象, 某种证据
It might be better at the moment
to find out what form this attack's going to take.
现在这个时候, 搞明白攻击可能会是什么形式, 可能更有用
- Jamie...  - What?
- Jamie...  - 什么?
That transistor radio that Vaughn gave you.
Have you still got it?
Vaughn 给你那个晶体管, 还在你那里吗？
Aye, here.
是, 这里
- Brigadier, have you any IE equipment here?
- Um, Jimmy, have we?
- 准将, 你这里有IE公司的设备不？  - 唔, Jimmy, 我们有吗？
Yes, we have, sir. A computer
and various radio and radar components.
有, 我们有, 长官．有电脑, 还有各种无线电、雷达器件
- May I see them, please?
- Certainly. Jimmy, would you...
- 我可以看看吗, 劳烦？  - 当然, Jimmy, 你可以...
- I'll show you, Doctor, it's this way.
- DOCTOR: Thank you.
- 我带你去, 博士, 在这边  - 谢谢你
- Ah, there you are, Packer. Everything going well?
- Yes, Mr Vaughn.
- 啊, 你来啦, Packer．一切都还好吧？  - 是的, Vaughn 先生？
Good. Time for our little experiment.
很好, 是时候看看我们的小实验了
Mr Vaughn, I don't think you should.../?
Vaughn 先生, 我觉得你不应该...
- We must try the machine, Gregory.
- But it's dangerous.
- 我们必须试试这台机器, Gregory  - 但这很危险
It would be even more dangerous
if we didn't try it.
如果我们不试一下的话, 就会更加危险
We must be sure we have an effective weapon
against the Cybermen.
我们必须得确保我们有一个有效的武器来对于赛博人
- You're going to try it on one of them?
- Why not?
- 你打算在他们身上做试验？  - 为什么不呢？
Revive it.
Uh, just enough to bring it out of its cocoon.
弄醒它fixme  啊, 把它从茧里面弄出来就可以了
MAN: Yes, sir.
好的, 先生
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Hold it there.
拿稳它fixme
Now, Gregory, connect the Professor's machine.
现在, Gregory, 连上教授的机器
- Mr Vaughn, please...  - Connect it!
- Vaughn 先生, 请你... - 连上!
- What emotion shall I induce?
- Fear!
- 我应该设定什么情绪？  - 害怕！
Let's see how the Cybermen will react to fear.
我们来看看赛博人对于害怕是如何应对的
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Increase the power.
加大功率
(DISTORTED HUMMING)
VAUGHN: More power!
GREGORY: That's all there is!
- 再开大！ - 已经是最大了！
(GUN FIRING)
VAUGHN: Quick!
快！
I told you, the machine isn't ready yet.
我告诉过你, 这台机器还没有准备好
- It's following the others into the sewers.
- Let it go.
- 它跟着它的同伴进入了下水道  - 让它去吧
It's gone mad. It could've killed us all.
它发疯了, 差点把我们都杀死了
Possibly, but I think we proved
that the Professor's machine can be effective.
有可能, 但我想我们证明了教授的机器是有效的
Get him to work on it, Gregory.
让他继续, Gregory
I want twice as much power
and I want directional control.
我要两倍功率, 还要有方向控制
Yeah, but what about that one?
好, 但那个怎么处理？
- You can't let it roam down there alone!
- Why not?
- 你不能让它在下面乱窜！  - 为什么不能？
- Well, it'll kill anything that gets in its way.
- Good.
- 它会杀死任何挡路的东西  - 很好
Anyone fool enough to be down
those sewers deserves to die.
任何想进入那些下水道的傻瓜, 都该死
This is rather like looking for
the proverbial needle in the proverbial...
这就跟俗话说的一样, 简直就是大海捞针...
- Just a minute...  - Found something?
- 等一下... - 发现什么了吗？
I don't know. Wait a minute.
我不知道, 等一下
Yes. Yes, I'm almost sure
that this is the same sort of circuit
是的, 是的, 我几乎可以确认, 这个电路基本是同一类型
that was in Jamie's radio.
跟 Jamie 的收音机里面那个一样
- But what does it do? - I've no idea.
- 但它有什么用？  - 我不知道
But it's certainly not part of that equipment.
Have a look.
但它显然不是这个设备的一部分, 你看一眼
But why put in a circuit if it doesn't do anything?
但是为什么要放一块什么也不干的电路？
Oh, it does something, all right.
The question is, what?
噢, 它是有某种用途的, 好吧．问题是, 什么用途？
COMMUNICATOR: One hour before invasion,
入侵开始前一小时
the Cyber-transmitter units will be
launched into orbit around Earth.
赛博转发装置会发射到地球轨道上
The effect will be immediate?
会立刻生效吗？
Yes, transmissions will penetrate all areas.
是的, 会发送到所有区域
And if it doesn't work?
但如果它不起作用呢？
Humans cannot resist Cyber-control.
人类抵抗不了赛博控制
Our forces will penetrate all areas
我们会突破所有区域
and select suitable humans
for cybernetic conversion.
然后选择合适的人类进行赛博转化
- Found anything?  - No. I'm afraid not.
- 找到什么了吗？  - 没, 恐怕还没找到
What I really need is laboratory facilities.
我真正需要的是实验室设备
I'm sure that this micromonolithic circuit
我确定这个微型单晶片电路
is something to do with the Cybermen's invasion plan.
与赛博人的入侵计划有某种关系
Perhaps we can find a lab for you to work in.
也许我们能找到一个实验室让你继续研究
Oh, no, that's no problem. I can go up to London
噢, 不, 这不是问题．我可以到伦敦去
and use Professor Watkins's laboratory
at Travers's house.
直接用 Travers 房子里 Watkins 教授的实验室